I'm sorry! I'm sorry! I'm sorry!
It's all right. I'm not gonna hurt you.
What do you want?
I thought you were...
What?
I don't know.
Help! Help!
Stop!
- What? What?
- It's okay. Come here.
It's okay. Calm down.
Everything's gonna be fine.
What was in there?
Just gimme a minute
to figure things out.
- Why were you afraid of that room?
- Gimme a minute I said.
How many people are in this thing?
Listen. We can't go
climbing around in here.
Why not?
- There are traps.
- What do you mean traps?
Booby traps. I looked
into a room down there and
something almost cut my head off.
Holy cats. Holy, holy cats.
You alright? Mister?
Worth!
Don't worry.
I hit my head.
Let me take a look at that.
I'm a doctor. It doesn't look that bad.
What the hell are you doing?
Hey, old man,
did you hear what I said?
Motion detectors. Integrated
into the walls. Tough to spot.
Oh god, oh god, oh god.
Wait a second.
Let's all just relax for a minute.
Does anybody remember
how they got here?
Perogies.
I was eating dinner.
Perogies. Cheese and potatoes.
I ran out of sour cream and then
I went to the fridge and then...
I don't know.
You? Leaven?
I, I just went to bed and...
What about you?
I just woke up here.
Middle of the night.
It's like Chile. They always come
in the middle of the night.
Who?
Only the goverment could build
something this ugly.
It ain't government.
- Then what is it?
- I don't know.
Aliens.
Please.
We're spooked enough as it is.
Let's rule out aliens for now and
concentrate on what we know.
My mom's gonna freak.
Rennes?
- I just won't be there. They'll freak.
- What do you think, Rennes?
We won't solve jack shit sittin' still.
I'm moving in a straight line
'till I get to the end.
All right, I tend to agree.
- Shouldn't we wait here?
- For what?
To see if anybody comes.
No one is gonna come.
Look. There is a way in here,
so there's gotta be a way out.
We can avoid
the traps using the boot.
Holloway is it?
What do you think? Look for an exit?
Okay.
What about you?
- It can't be that simple.
- It won't be that simple.
Look around.
Take a good long looksee.
'Cause I got a feeling
it's looking at us.
I just want to wake up.
Leaven. We can do this.
We just have to stay calm
and work together as a team.
There's gonna be a lot of people
looking for us on the outside.
I'm a cop.
All right?
- You're a cop?
- Yeah.
I'm gonna get you out of here.
I promise.
You gotta be with me on this one.
Okay.
Boot it!
Clean.
That one sounded closer.
It's mechanical. It seems
to come at regular intervals.
Maybe it's the ventilation system.
- No vents.
- No kidding, I'm boiling.
What is it?
Serial numbers?
Room numbers.
They're different in each room.
Oh great. There are only 566 millions
400 thousand rooms in this thing.
Well, there better not be?
We have about 3 days
without food and water
before we are too weak to move.
Well, they have to feed us,
don't they?
Holloway.
Oh, we have heat, stress, physical
exsection, i.e., dehydratation,
headaches, dizziness, disorientation,
confused mental processes.
The body eventually begins
to break down its own tissue.
Suck on it.
Keeps the saliva flowing.
- What?
- The air seems dry in there.
Trapped?
Molecular chemical sensor.
Why the hell didn't
the boot set it off?
The boot's not alive.
Detects hydrogen sulphide
excreted from the skin.
How is it you know
so much about sensors, Renz?
Renn. Not Renz. It's French.
Fine, you're French.
I'm asking how you...
Renn. Sensor expert,
about the right age.
I don't believe it.
- This guy is the Wren.
- The what?
He's the Wren. The Bird of Attica.
Flew the coop on 6 major prisons.
Seven.
You're kidding, right?
You can get us out.
Maybe.
An escape artist.
Yeah, I'm Harry fucking Houdini.
The only reason I dragged you
this far is 'cause I need your boots.
If you don't smarten up,
I'll be gone like that.
No more talking.
No more guessing.
Don't even think about nothing
that's not right in front of you.
That's the real challenge.
You got to save yourselves
from yourselves.
Merde.
Get him out!
Oh my god!
So, it was electro chemical or
whatever, right? And he missed it.
The Wren. That's great!
That's fuckin' great!
All right. It's time
to reassess this place.
I've been over it again and again.
Why would they throw
innocent people in here?
Are we being punished?
I've never done anything
to deserve this.
Forget about all that!
You can't see the big picture
from in here, so don't try.
Keep your head down.
Keep it simple.
Just look at what's in front of you.
That's what he said.
Start with us.
We got an escape artist and a cop.
There's gotta be a reason for that.
You're doctor, Holloway. It gives you
a function, a reason, right?
No. It's just makes me go why me
and why not one of the other
10 million doctors out there.
Leaven, what are you?
Nothing. I just go to school.
I hang out with my friends.
- What else?
- There's nothing else.
My parents are these people.
I live with them. I'm boring.
I think we have to ask
the big questions.
What does it want?
What is it thinking?
One down, four to go.
Why don't you tell us
what your purpose is, Worth?
Often wondered that myself.
I'm just a guy.
I work in an office building,
doing office building stuff.
I wasn't exactly bursting with
"joie de vivre" before I got here.
Life just sucks in general.
- I can't stand that attitude.
- Because he's right.
What's your purpose, Quentin?
Kids, three of them.
I haven't made my peace yet.
I'm getting out of here,
no matter what.
That's where
my strength comes from.
You, people,
find yours wherever you got it.
For Christ's sake, Worth.
What do you live for?
Don't you have a wife or
a girlfriend, or something?
No. I've got a pretty fine
collection of pornography.
Oh, nice, nice.
I haven't got anybody either, but
I'm not giving up! I am pissed off.
They came into our homes!
They stripped us bare.
They took my rings, they took...
...oh, my amethyst.
I wanna know who's responsible.
Leaven. Your glasses?
You don't need them?
They're for reading.
Well they took off our jewelry,
but why they put these on you.
If nothing is random,
why are they here?
Leaven. What do you do
in school? Math?
What can they mean?
149.
Prime numbers. I can't believe
I didn't see it before.
See what?
It seems like, if any
of these numbers are prime,
then the room's trapped.
645, 645... That's not prime.
372... no.
649...
Well, 11 times 59.
It's not prime either.
So that room is safe.
Wait.
How can you make that assumption
based on one prime number trap?
I'm not. The incinerator thing
was prime 083.
The molecular chemical thing had
137. The acid room had 149.
You remember all that in your head?
I have a facility for it.
Leaven, you beautiful brain.
Boot it.
Okay, out of the way.
Brains before beauty.
Safe, safe.
Prime numbers! Prime numbers!
Oh, how long have we been in here?
Nine or ten hours.
How do you know?
Five o'clock shadow. Last thing
I remember was shaving.
I guess
I missed breakfast or lunch...
or whatever.
Don't worry.
I'll be home in time for dinner.
If we get out, I'll make you dinner.
You got a date.
Doin' good.
I need to smoke.
I'd smoke a butt off a sidewalk.
Holloway.
Just reel yourself in a bit. Come on.
We're moving along.
Things are looking up.
Ok, ok. You are right.
I quit smoking years ago.
I just need to be occupied.
Talk then. Have a conversation.
What kind of doctor are you anyway?
Oh, you know, the free kind.
Come on. Help me.
Tell me about your rug rats.
We have three boys. 9, 7 and 5.
Good God. Poor woman.
There's no way I'd survive that.
She didn't either.
She's not dead,
we're just separated.
I'm sorry.
I can't just shoot the breeze.
These numbers aren't prime.
Okay, clear.
Excuse me, sorry.
You, could try and
help me out here, buddy.
No, I couldn't.
This one's trapped too.
We have to backtrack?
Not yet.
Read them to me.
- What are you, his coat rack?
- Oh, please!
It's stuck.
Look out.
This room is green.
Holloway?
Hi there.
This room is green.
Yes, it is.
I wanna go back to the blue room.
What is it? Shock or what?
I think he's mentally handicapped.
I like the blue room.
- Jesus Christ.
- He almost broke my neck.
Hey there, are you all alone?
You want to hold my hand, honey?
Butter first, then honey, Kazan.
Butter first, then honey...
- How'd he survive?
- I want to go back to the blue room.
There's lots of blue rooms.
We'll find you another real soon.
This is just way too bizarre.
Well, you just worry
about your numbers then.
Go on. I'll look after him.
Safe. Obviously,
since he almost fell on my head.
Should we go for a walk, Kazan?
You want to go for a walk?
Let's not make him do
the climbing thing right away.
Holloway...
Hol-Io-way.
Could they have taken us
all the way to New Mexico?
What are you
talking about, Holloway?
I'm talking about where do you
hide something this big.
At least he's good for something.
I'm sorry to shake
your foundations, Quentin,
but you have no idea
where your tax dollars go.
Free clinic doctors?
Only the military
industrial complex could afford
to build something this size.
Holloway, what is
the military industrial complex?
Have you ever been there?
I'm telling you,
it's not that complex.
How would you know
from where you are?
Who do you think
the establishment is?
It's just guys like me.
Their desks are bigger,
but their jobs are't.
They don't conspire...
they buy boats.
No, this place is...
remember Scaramanga?
The bad guy in
"The Man With The Golden Gun".
It's some rich
psycho's entertainment.
Is that what you think?
Clear.
Ok. You are a cop.
Single bullet theory. Right on.
- Gas!
- Holloway, get back here!
It's okay.
I just swallowed my button.
I hate this. I hate this.
Your boy is having
a conniption fit in there.
It's like cramming without coffee.
- She needs a break.
- She can do it.
They don't look like prime to me.
Is that your two bits worth, Worth?
For what it's worth.
- Well?
- Well, he's right. Not prime.
Stop! In front of you!
What is it?
Shut up!
I don't know what happened.
It wasn't prime.
Quentin, hold still.
- Somebody stops that racket.
- Worth!
Leave the boots.
And shut the fucking door!
I had a feeling
about that fucking guy.
He knew about that trap.
These numbers aren't prime.
Then your number system failed,
but he knew...
Knew what? How would he know?
You are the paranoid one,
think about it.
His only function so far has been
to kick us when we're down.
So he has a bad attitude. Are you
saying, that makes him a spy?
Trust me on this. It's my job
to read people like an X-Ray.
He doesn't like red rooms.
So what happened?
- You saw what happened.
- Quentin!
I guess the numbers are
more complicated that I thought.
Maybe they mean nothing at all.
No. It means
they are more involved.
They've worked for us up 'till now,
haven't they?
I just need more time with them.
Well, we need to rest anyway.
Well. That's handy. 'Cause there's
not a fuck of a lot else we can do.
Are they telling you anything?
They're not tarot cards.
Do you have any idea how many
variables I have to consider
before I can
decipher numbers this size?
They don't reveal
themselves right away.
They're like people.
Oh, gross.
Oh, not here honey.
Over in the corner.
Well, he's just peeing.
Jesus Christ.
That's excellent.
Now it totally reeks in here!
You find this all
pretty funny, don't you?
What's your
fucking problem, Worth?
Even Holloway's
holding up better than you.
Get over there and help her with him.
That's your job. Babysitter.
Jawohl, Kommandant.
Somebody has to take
responsability around here.
And that somebody has to be you.
Not all of us have
the luxury of playing nihilist.
Not all of us are
conceited enough to play hero.
This is a will to live.
Everybody's got it,
Worth, even you.
Especially you,
hiding behind that cynical front.
A will to live.
That's the warm,
cosy feeling deep inside.
Thanks Quentin, I'm a new man.
Oh, poor Worth. Nobody loves me.
If that's the chip
on your shoulder, why
did you lug it all this way?
Why didn't you
just lie down and die?
Do it.
Show us you have some backbone
and jump in the sushi machine.
Be a man.
Thought so.
Fuck you Quentin!
I don't wanna die.
I'm just being realistic.
Do you think they'd go to all
the trouble to build this thing
if we could just walk out?
Do you think
they would have left us clues
and let us beat it so far
if there wasn't a way out?
You think we matter? We don't.
Put us out of your misery so we can
get on with getting out of here.
You're not getting out of here!
- Yes, we are!
- No, you're not!
- There is no way out of here!
Gotchya.
How do you know that?
Answer the question, Worth.
Oh, god.
Who are you?
I'm the poison.
I designed the outer shell.
The what?
The shell. The sarcophagus.
You built this thing?
Not this part. The exterior.
I don't know anything about the
numbers or anything else in here.
I was contracted to draw
plans for a hollow shell.
A cube.
A cube? Why didn't you tell us?
For God's sake, Worth,
you knew what it was.
No.
Worth. You're lying.
Was not at first.
Who's behind it?
I don't know.
Who hired you?
I didn't ask.
I never even left my office.
I talked on the phone to some
people, other guys like me.
Specialists,
working on small details.
Nobody knew what it was.
Nobody cared.
Bullshit.
You knew from square one.
Look at him. He is up
to his eyeballs in this thing.
No, Quentin.
That's how they stay hidden.
You keep everyone separated
so the left hand doesn't know
what the right hand is doing.
The brain
never comes out in the open.
Whose brain?
It's all the same machine, right!
The Pentagone, multinational
corporations, the police.
If you do one little job,
you build a widget in Saskatoon,
and the next thing you know
it's two miles under
the desert, the essential
component of a death machine.
I was right.
All along, my whole life,
I knew it. I told you, Quentin.
Nobody's every gonna
call me paranoid again.
We gotta get out of here and
blow the lid of this thing!
Holloway, you don't get it.
Then help me,
please, I need to know.
This may be hard
for you to understand,
but there's no conspiracy.
Nobody is in charge.
It's a headless blunder operating
under the illusion of a master plan.
Can you grasp that?
Big brother is not watching you.
What kind of
fuckin' explanation is that?
It's the best you are gonna get.
I looked, and the only conclusion
I could come to is that
there is nobody up there.
Somebody had to say
yes to this thing.
What thing?
Only we know what it is.
- We have no idea what it is.
- We know more than anybody else.
I mean, somebody might have
known sometime before they go,
they got fired, or
voted out, or sold it,
but if this place
ever had a purpose,
and it got miscommunicated,
or lost in a shuffle.
I mean, this is and accident,
a forgotten perpetual
public works project.
Do you think anybody
wants to ask questions?
All they want is
a clear conscience,
and a fat paycheck.
I leaned on my shovel
for months on this one.
This was a great job!
Why put people in it?
Because it's here. You have
to use it or you admit it's pointless.
But it is pointless.
Quentin. That's my point.
What have we come to?
It's so much worse than I thought.
Not really. Just more pathetic.
You make me sick, Worth.
I make me sick too.
We're both part of the system.
I drew a box, you walk a beat.
It's like you said, Quentin,
is keep your head down,
keep it simple,
just look at what's in front of you.
I mean, nobody wants to see
the big picture.
Life's too complicated.
I mean, let's face it, the reason
we're here is that it's out of control.
This is how we ruin the world?
Well, have you been on glue
all your lives?
I've felt guilty for ruining
the world since I was like 7.
God, if you need someone
to blame, throw a rock.
Well, I feel better.
That's why you stayed with us.
To confess.
You still looking
for someone to bust, Quentin?
Quentin! Stop it! Stop it!
We need him.
What for?
Have you gone absolutely mad?
He's the only one who knows
anything about the place.
- Worth.
- Hi.
- So there's this outer shell.
- Yeah.
- And it's a cube, right? Like this.
- I assume so.
- Are there any doors?
- There's one door.
- Where?
- Wherever the door guy put it.
Six guesses, and
it's sealed from the outside.
And, what are the dimensions
of the outer shell?
434 square feet.
May I?
Come on, honey, slide over.
14 by 14 by 14.
The inner cube can't be flush
with the shell wall, there's a space.
One cube?
I don't know, it makes sense.
Ok. The biggest the cube
can be then is...
26 rooms high,
26 rooms across, so...
17.576 rooms.
Seventeen thousand, five hundred
and seventy-six rooms?
That makes me queasy.
Descartes!
- Leaven, you are a genius.
- What? What?
Cartesian coordinates. Of course,
coded cartesian coordinates.
They're used in geometry to plot
points on a 3-dimensional graph.
In English, slower.
Bonjour?
These numbers are markers,
and grid reference, like latitude
and longitude on a map.
The numbers tell us where
we are inside the cube.
Well, where are we?
It works.
Okay. All I have to do is add
the numbers together.
The X coordinate is 19...
Y is 26 rooms...
So that places us...
...seven rooms from the edge.
All right, let's go.
Just out of curiosity, I mean,
don't hit me again, or anything...
but what are you gonna do
when you get there?
Maybe we can get the door open.
What we need is to do figure out
how to get around the traps.
I'm dealing with that Holloway.
I'm looking for
practical solutions here.
Well, you haven't found any yet.
We cut the risk with the numbers
and the boot. Worth will go in first.
No, he won't Quentin!
We take turns!
Relax.
Room for two in there?
What's the matter?
These coordinates. 14, 27, 14.
- What about 'em?
- They don't make sense.
Assuming the cube is
26 rooms across,
there can't be
a coordinate larger than 26.
If this were right, then
we would be outside of the cube.
No, not outside of the cube.
I guess that means
we're not having dinner.
Trap. Trap. Trap. Trap.
Trap!
Sound activated.
Lovely.
How come the sound of the door
opening didn't set it off?
Must be rigged to ignore it.
So that's it. The edge is
surrounded by traps.
Well, I guess we have to backtrack,
and try somewhere else.
Who knows how many detours
we'll have to take.
I say we cross the bitch.
Right!
How many boots do we have left,
Holloway?
Get it off him.
We know how it works.
We just have to be quiet.
That's pretty fucking quiet.
I'm glad you're on side,
Worth, 'cause... you're up.
And he is not coming.
Of course, he is.
- No way.
- We are not leaving him behind.
He's unpredictable.
When we get to the edge,
we can come back for him.
But he'll get somebody killed here.
Am I right?
Shame on you.
Will you look at yourselves?
What have you turned into?
They may have taken our lives away,
but we are still human beings.
That's all we've got left.
We'll come back for him.
That's a lie and you know it.
He'll be quiet.
- What are you doing?
- I'm gonna wait for him.
- No.
- You go out, I'm here.
Okay.
This way.
- You fucking fuck!
- That's enough!
- He is a trap!
- Let him go right now!
The law of the jungle!
He is endangering the pack!
Let him go, you Nazi!
What did you call me?
Quentin, you let
that innocent boy go.
You listen to me, woman.
Everyday I mop up
after your bleeding heart.
The only reason you
even exist is because I keep you.
I know your type,
no kids, no man to fuck you.
So you go around outraged,
sticking your nose up
other people's assholes,
sniffing their business!!!
You missed your boat, Holloway.
You're all dried up
inside there, aren't you?
That's your fucking problem.
How dare you say that to her?
You don't know her, Quentin.
None of us know each other here.
- Oh, I do.
- No you don't.
No wonder your wife left you.
All that bottled up anger.
And a thing for young girls.
God help you, Quentin.
Did you smack
your kids around too?
Is anybody besides me interested in
what's on the other side of that door?
Open it.
Door number six? Not number one?
Door number two?
Open the fuckin' thing.
Oh, sunshine.
Night time.
My old friend, the shell.
It's there. Morning!
Hang on to me.
I can't see shit.
Nothin' to hang on to.
We gotta try something.
We gotta see
if the door's over there.
Someone has to swing
over there, and take a look.
Swing?
We make a rope,
out of clothes.
Take 'em off.
I'll tie it around myself.
Ah, yeah, and you're gonna go.
You weight like 500 ponds,
it'll snap in two seconds.
I'm the lightest.
Forget it.
I'll go.
I'm going, Holloway.
She's right Quentin,
you're too heavy.
I'm the lightest after Leaven.
Anyway, it's my turn.
How long did you know
people were being put in here?
A couple of months.
That's not long,
if you consider your whole life.
I am.
You opened my eyes Worht.
That's something.
David.
Helen.
You're such a Helen.
That's as far as you go.
There's nothing down here.
Hold tight.
I try swinging over there.
Brace yourselves,
I'm gonna try again.
- Okay, one more time.
- Hurry, you're getting heavy.
What the hell's going on?
Get up here now!
- Quentin!
- Have you got her?
- What's going on?
- Quentin, is she okay?
She... slipped.
Holloway?
Hey, shhh...
Come on, Kazan.
Kazan, will you please
stop doing that?
Leaven, you got be strong,
sweetheart.
Don't even talk to me.
We gotta get down to the bottom.
It will be easier to get on
to the shell from there.
It's a long fucking way
with only one boot.
But we gotta do it
before we get too weak.
You gotta keep
cracking the numbers, Leaven.
I can't think anymore.
Sure you can. It's your gift.
It's not a gift. It's just a brain.
Let her sleep for a while. We haven't
slept in fuck knows how long.
All right.
One hour.
How the fuck are you gonna know
how long an hour is?
An hour is as long as I say.
What are you doing?
We have to make it down
to the bottom.
It'll be quiet there, and
you can concentrate.
- You just want to leave them?
- They're traps, Leaven.
We are the key.
I'll get us down there.
You think us out.
Believe in me!
Try and see what I see,
how my mind works.
The flash when I look into someone's
head like a fucking X-ray.
I looked through the walls.
I dreamed him at his desk,
designing everything.
He can't let you solve the puzzle,
see, 'cause
there is a purpose.
We are the purpose. The cube...
...is us.
- Quentin.
- We fit. Like numbers.
A man and a woman.
Two halves of the equation.
I take you down, the perfect key.
I slip you in the lock.
Leaven, it's time to go down.
Get away from her.
Leaven, they're fuckin' spies.
Him, the retard.
Holloway, had outside
information about my family...
but she slipped up, didn't she?
She crossed the line!
You dropped her.
Just go, Quentin.
Give us the boot, you pig!
You don't want the boot.
You want to came with us, Worth?
Down the hatch.
What the fuck's with him?
How did...
It's, it's, it's the Wren.
It's the old Wrenster.
How could...
We've been going around in circles.
That can't be.
- Where are we?
- I don't know!
Where are we?
You figure it out!
You haven't done anything.
All you do is freak out you,
murderer!
I guess you were right, Worth.
There is no way out of here.
Get away from me.
Wasn't Rennes killed in that room?
How come there's nothing out there?
It's the edge.
We weren't at the edge before.
Where's the room that killed Rennes?
Fuck off!
Oh, that was good.
What difference does it make?
We're dead anyways.
Hey, listen to what I'm saying.
There was a room there before.
We haven't been moving in circles.
The rooms have.
- Of course.
- The rooms?
That explains
the thunder and the shaking.
We've been shifting the whole time.
It's the only logical explanation.
I'm such an idiot!
- What are you on to, Leaven?
- Give me a minute.
The numbers are markers,
points on a map, right?
Right.
How do you map a point
that keeps moving?
Permutations.
Permu what?
A list of all the coordinates
that the room passes through.
Like a map, that tells you
where the rooms starts,
how many times it moves,
and where it moves to.
The numbers tell you all that?
I don't know,
see, I've only been looking
at one point on the map,
which is probably
the starting position.
All I saw was what the cube looked
like before it started to move.
Okay, so it's moving.
How do we get out?
27.
I know where the exit is.
Where?
- Stay away from me.
- Back off, Quentin.
I just wanna know.
Don't you wanna know?
You remember that room
we passed through before,
the one with the coordinate
larger than 26?
What about it?
That coordinate placed the room
outside the cube.
A bridge.
Right.
But only in its original position.
What are you talking about?
Look.
The room starts off as a bridge,
and then it moves its way
through the maze,
which is where we ran into it.
But at some point,
it must return to its original position.
- So a bridge is only a bridge.
- For a short period of time.
This thing is like
a giant combination lock.
When the rooms are in their
starting position, the lock is open.
But when they move
out of alignment, the lock closes.
With a structure this size,
it must take days
for the rooms
to complete a full cycle.
So, when does it open?
Don't.
To find the original coordinates,
the numbers are added together.
To find the permutations, they're
subtracted from one another.
That's it!
This room moves to zero,
1 and -1 on the X-axis.
2, 5 and -7 on Y.
And 1, and -1 and zero on Z.
And what does that mean?
You suck at math?
Okay, I need the room numbers
around us as reference points.
666, 897, 466.
- 567, 898. Okay?
- Yes.
And 545.
Did you get that?
656, 778, 462.
That's enough.
X is 17, Y is 25 and Z is 14.
Which means
this room makes 2 more moves
before returning
to its original position.
- Do we have time?
- Maybe.
Then let's go!
Can you work
the traps into this system?
Fuck the traps.
Let's get to the bridge.
You threw out our last boot,
you fucking idiot.
- Technically, I can identify the traps.
- Technically?
At first, I thought
that they were identified
by prime numbers,
but they are not.
They are identified by numbers
that are the power of a prime.
- Ok, so?
- Can you calculate that?
The numbers are huge.
But you can, right? She can.
I'd have to calculate
the number of factors in each set.
Maybe if I had a computer.
- You don't need a computer.
- Yes I do.
- Figure it out.
- I can't.
I'm not dying in a fucking rat maze!
Look. Nobody in the whole world
could do it mentally.
Look at the numbers. 567898545.
There's no way I can factor that!
I can't even start on 567!
It's astronomical!
2.
Astronomical.
What did you say?
Before that.
Factors.
How many factors Kazan?
Of 567.
2.
What, are you fucking kidding?
Kazan. How many
factors does 30 have?
3.
- How about 7?
- 1. Gum drop.
I don't have any gum drops.
Gum drop.
Kazan. I'll give you a whole box
of gum drops for each answer.
Gum drops come in bags.
Okay. You want them in bags,
they are coming in bags.
I don't like the red ones.
- 898.
- 2.
- 545.
He's giving us the factors.
Astronomical.
You're telling me
telethon boy is a genius?
By those numbers,
the room should be safe.
Only one way to find out.
Don't!
Safe.
Kazan, my man.
What's the number, buddy boy?
Hey, right here, look here!
Make him do it!
Kazan, we're gonna do
some numbers now, okay?
We like to do numbers, right?
- Prime numbers.
- That's right.
- Can you tell me the factor of 656?
- 2.
- 779?
- 462?
- 3.
- Clear.
- Move!
Come on. Come on,
let's go. You too, Worth!
Move your scawny ass, Worth.
I'm not through with you yet.
Leaven, open that door.
Get Einstein
working on the numbers.
Oh, jeez.
- Go!
- Worth!
- Hurry!
- Leaven!
563!
- Please, Kazan, 563?
- You fuckers, you're dead!
- 2.
- Clear!
- 1.
- Trapped!
- Check the floor.
- Is he dead?
Not quite.
Not even close. Worth,
I'm getting out of here and
I'll feed you to
a fucking trap on the way.
Where is he?
Come here. I said
come here right nooowwww!!
Gotchya. That way.
- 2.
- Clear!
- 4.
Guess that proves our theory.
Numbers.
- 4, 2, 3.
- Clear.
Kazan!
Listen.
- He hasn't moved far.
- I'll go find him.
What do you think?
You don't have a lot of lives left.
- Kazan!
- I didn't move.
Yeah, good. But you're gonna have
to climb up here, okay?
I don't like that.
14, 26, 14.
Worth, get back here right now!
Five bags of gum drops.
27 bags total.
27 bags. Deal.
This room's next move
takes it to the bridge!
We're coming!
Over here!
Move it! We don't have
much time. Come on.
Worth? Worth?
This better be it.
It should be.
Where?
Oh, well!
Give me a minute. Be patient.
- So, guess what?
- No.
This is the room we started in.
I was right. We should
never have moved in the first place.
The bridge.
Red.
Kazan?
- 4, 2, 4.
- Clear!
Worth!
Go ahead.
What are you doing?
You can't quit now.
It's not your fault!
I have nothing to live for out there.
What is out there?
Boundless human stupidity.
I can live with that.
Noooooo!!!
Kazan! Get out through the door!
Red, Kazan.